# RAYMOND NWAMBUONWO SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

## **Summary**

Software Developer with a background in education and solution-focused development with MERN and JAMstack technologies. Utilizing the MERN and JAMstack technologies enables me to develop efficient, secure, and scalable full-stack web applications for an optimum web experience. As a former educator, I appreciate how programming increases my aptitude for learning and allows me to apply newfound concepts for efficient development practices.

### **Employment**

Code Differently Junior Software Developer Remote,USA Aug. 2020 to Current

- Improved educational operations by creating a two-phased roadmap in which; phase one
  consisted of lessons delivered via video and live demos; phase two consisted of project-based
  learning where junior developers work on real-world applications utilizing technology such as
  HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MERN, JAMstack, etc.
- Develop and design a multitude of web applications in collaboration with a fortune 500 company towards teaching 20 junior engineers full-stack technologies in preparation for work opportunities.
- Leading a team of 5 software engineer instructors in daily standup meetings in an agile environment to complete tasks in a timely and efficient manner.

# General Assembly, Software Engineering Immersive Program

Washington, D.C. Sept. 2019 to Jan. 2020

- Project-focused intensive program with an emphasis on Mongo, Express, React, and JavaScript (MERN) technical stack.
- Collaborated with a team of over 25 software engineers and UI/UX designers on the design, implementation, testing, and documentation of client projects in an agile environment.
- Designed and developed responsive web applications using technologies such as HTML, CSS, Javascript, and React.JS.
- Developed command-line and back-end focused applications with databases utilizing technologies such as Python, Node.js, Express.js, Django, MongoDB, and SQL.
- Utilized a hands-on approach to develop real-world applications while maintaining two GitHub (GitHub & GH Enterprise) profiles with a combined commit history of 400+ contributions.

### University of Maryland

Academic Advisor

Largo, Maryland Aug. 2018 to Aug. 2019

- Provided excellent customer service to a diverse student population by advising on strategic planning, SMART goals, and class enrollment.
- Managed progress of student academics with Salesforce and PeopleSoft software ensuring compliance with degree audits and transfer evaluations.

# **Projects**

#### **Portfolio**

Portfolio web app with CRUD functionality utilizing JAMstack, Firebase, and Tailwind to showcase
my past and current projects, lessons, and blog posts.

### I-Opener

 Photography portfolio web application with CRUD functionality built using the JAMstack, a Sanity.io Headless CMS backend, and Tailwind for styling.

#### T.A.S.A.B

• Meditation and Motivation web application built with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.

#### 010

 Skillset web application built using the MERN Stack that tracks skillset progress which is then stored in an internal API.

### Rolodex

Command-line interface application "Rolodex" utilizing Python that stores users' contact
information within a PostgreSQL database.

### **Contact**

- **RaymondNwambuonwo@gmail.com**
- RaymondNwambuonwo.com
- **4** 347.748.3900
- **♥** Washington D.C.
- in linkedin.com/in/raymondnwambuonwo
- RaymondNwambuonwo

### **Education**

General Assembly, Software Engineering Immersive, Washington, DC

Certificate of Completion Software Engineering Immersive 2020

State University of New York College at Buffalo, Buffalo, NY

M.S. Higher Education & Student Affairs Administration 2018

State University of New York College at Oswego B.A. Mass Communications 2014

### **Skills**

#### FRONT END DEVELOPMENT

**Bootstrap** 

CSS

HTML JavaScript

ReactJS

Material UI

Tailwind

NextJs

#### **BACK END DEVELOPMENT**

**Express** 

MongoDB

NPM

Python PostgreSOL

RESTful APIs

Node.JS

Sanity.10

Firebase

#### DEV TOOLS

**Agile Methodologies** 

Github

Heroku

MongoDB Atlas

Netlify

Postman

Git

Linux